Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a very technical, very advanced lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节非常专业、非常高级的课程。
This is all about one of my favorite subjects.
这完全是我最喜欢的主题之一。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to talk about music, but specifically we're going to talk about the piano and learning
我们要谈论音乐，但具体来说，我们要谈论钢琴以及学习
how to play the piano.
如何弹钢琴。
So we're going to talk about very specific vocab related to this instrument.
所以我们会讨论与这种乐器相关的非常具体的词汇。
Right.
对。
So piano and playing music, not listening to music.
所以是钢琴和演奏音乐，而不是听音乐。
Right.
对。
And there are a lot of interesting words and phrases here.
这里有很多有趣的单词和短语。
Some of them actually come from foreign languages like Italian.
有些实际上来自外语，比如意大利语。
So listen up.
所以注意听。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿就回来。
And when we come back, we'll be talking about what these words and phrases mean.
等我们回来时，我们会讨论这些单词和短语的意思。
Hi Cody.
嗨，Cody。
How did practicing go this week?
这周练习得怎么样？
Well, I had several tests and an oral presentation this week, so I didn't get a chance to memorize
嗯，这周我有几场考试和一个口头报告，所以没来得及背
the second page, but I think I mastered the tricky section.
第二页，但我觉得我掌握了那个棘手的部分。
Great.
很好。
Let's start with some scales and arpeggios first.
我们先从一些音阶和琶音开始吧。
Good, good.
好，好。
This week, work on keeping the rhythm steady when you play the last part with the 16th
这周，注意在演奏最后那部分十六分音符时保持节奏稳定。
notes.
Now let's take a look at this tricky section.
现在让我们看看这个棘手的部分。
Charlene, before I start, I was wondering if it was okay if I put a small crescendo
Charlene，在我开始之前，我想问一下，我能不能在这里加一个小渐强，
in here and then a decrescendo back to pianissimo again over here.
然后在这里再渐弱回到极弱音。
Hmm, it might work.
嗯，可能行得通。
I'll have to hear it.
我得听听看。
Show me what you've done.
给我展示一下你做了什么。
Not bad.
还不错。
It was horrible.
太糟糕了。
I played it much better at home.
我在家弹得好多了。
It's just nerves.
只是紧张而已。
Just play the right hand for now.
现在只弹右手部分。
One, two, three, four, five, six, ta, ti, triple e, ti.
一、二、三、四、五、六、嗒、嘀、三连音、嘀。
Good, good.
好，好。
Don't forget the accidentals.
别忘了临时记号。
The key signature says that note should be a G sharp, but now it's a G natural.
调号说那个音符应该是升G，但现在它是还原G。
Now add the bass clef.
现在加上低音谱号。
You're going too fast.
你弹得太快了。
Remember the tempo for this piece is andante.
记住这首曲子的速度是行板。
Is that better?
这样好点了吗？
Yes, much better.
是的，好多了。
Watch where you lift your foot off the pedal.
注意你抬脚离开踏板的位置。
What was that?
那是什么？
Sorry.
对不起。
The stretch for that octave is always hard to make.
那个八度的跨度总是很难做到。
That's okay.
没关系。
Keep going.
继续。
You're moving ahead by leaps and bounds.
你进步神速。
Watch your dynamics.
注意你的力度变化。
Keep your elbows lifted.
保持手肘抬起。
Remember to stroke the keys.
记住要轻触琴键。
Don't pound.
不要猛敲。
That's better.
这样好多了。
Remember that as a pianist or any other musician, your technique will be what separates you
记住，作为一名钢琴家或任何其他音乐家，你的技巧将是你
from the pack just as much or as more so as your musicianship.
从众人中脱颖而出的关键，其重要性不亚于你的音乐素养。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
You probably noticed that there are a lot of ways to describe certain aspects of playing
你可能注意到了，有很多方式可以描述弹钢琴的某些方面。
the piano.
They talked about scales and all that stuff.
他们谈到了音阶之类的东西。
Why don't we take a deeper look at this vocab in Language Takeaway Part 1.
我们不如在“语言要点第一部分”中更深入地看看这些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
The first part of the lesson is the warm-up.
课程的第一部分是热身。
That's when we start to get our fingers moving and really stretch out.
那是我们开始活动手指、真正伸展的时候。
This is an important part of any musician's routine because it's also a way to practice
这是任何音乐家日常练习的重要部分，因为它也是练习一些非常基础、非常根本的东西的方式。
some very basic, very fundamental things.
The first of which is a scale.
第一个就是音阶。
Okay.
好的。
So actually, Cody started warming up with some scales.
所以实际上，Cody 开始用一些音阶来热身。
So what exactly are scales?
那么音阶到底是什么？
Well, basically, there are different musical notes.
嗯，基本上，有各种不同的音符。
Some people know them as do, re, mi, fa, sol, la, ti, do.
有些人知道它们是 do、re、mi、fa、sol、la、ti、do。
Some people call them C, D, E, F, G, A, B, C. But each of those and many others have
有些人叫它们 C、D、E、F、G、A、B、C。但每一个音符以及其他许多音符都有
scales.
音阶。
So that's eight notes together.
所以那是八个音符连在一起。
Okay.
好的。
So basically, when you're playing scales, you're just playing a sequence of these eight
所以基本上，当你弹音阶时，你只是在弹奏这八个音符的一个序列。
notes.
笔记。
Right.
对。
Going up or down.
上行或下行。
Okay.
好的。
To warm up.
热身。
And what about an arpeggio?
那琶音呢？
I think this is Italian, right?
我觉得这是意大利语，对吧？
Definitely.
绝对是。
Arpeggio is another kind of warm-up where you're not playing every single note.
琶音是另一种热身方式，你不是弹奏每一个音符。
You're playing some notes in a scale.
你是在音阶中弹奏一些音符。
All right.
好的。
So, la, da, da, da, da, da, da, da.
所以，啦，哒，哒，哒，哒，哒，哒，哒。
That's an arpeggio.
那就是琶音。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, and as you said, these are usually for warm-ups, right?
那么，正如你所说，这些通常用于热身，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
They're also very important because they come into play later when you're talking about
它们也非常重要，因为后来当你谈论一首歌或一段音乐所在的调时，它们会发挥作用。
the key that a song or a piece of music is in.
所以这有助于你记住某些音乐所在的调。
So this helps you memorize the key that some music is in.
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So I think related to this is the rhythm of the piece that you're playing.
所以我认为与此相关的是你演奏的乐曲的节奏。
That's right.
没错。
So rhythm is really important.
所以节奏真的很重要。
You can even say, you know, he's got rhythm or they have rhythm.
你甚至可以说，你知道，他有节奏感或者他们有节奏感。
It's a way to describe the beat of a kind of music.
这是一种描述某种音乐节拍的方式。
So sometimes it has to do with how fast or how slow something is.
所以有时它跟某样东西的快慢有关。
Other times it has to do with the way that the notes work together.
其他时候则跟音符如何配合有关。
For example, a steady beat would be one, two, three, four, one, two, three, four.
例如，稳定的节拍就是一、二、三、四，一、二、三、四。
This is a complicated beat.
这是一个复杂的节拍。
It goes ta, ti, tri, po, li, ta, ti, tri, po, li.
它听起来是嗒、嘀、嗒、嘀、嗒、嘀、嗒、嘀、嗒、嘀。
So this is a very difficult kind of rhythm.
所以这是一种非常难的节奏。
Okay.
好的。
So the rhythm is just kind of, it gives you how fast, how slow it is.
所以节奏就是，它告诉你快慢如何。
And I guess if you can take a look at notes and you can play it in many different rhythms,
我想如果你能看音符，你可以用很多不同的节奏来演奏它，
but not necessarily they're going to sound correct.
但不一定听起来会正确。
Right.
对。
And actually it's interesting.
实际上这很有趣。
In English we also have a group of instruments that are called rhythm instruments.
在英语中，我们还有一组乐器叫做节奏乐器。
So this would be like the drums.
所以这就像是鼓的部分。
Okay.
好的。
So it gives the beat.
所以它提供了节拍。
Yes.
是的。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, moving on, I think some other Italian words popped up in here when they talked about
嗯，继续往下，我觉得他们提到了一些意大利语词汇，比如
crescendo and decrescendo.
渐强和渐弱。
Right.
没错。
So crescendo is when something becomes louder.
渐强就是声音逐渐变大。
So I can make a crescendo.
所以我可以做一个渐强。
But a decrescendo, de in Italian, just like in English means it's the opposite.
而渐弱，意大利语中的“de”，就像英语里一样，表示相反的意思。
So it means it's getting really softer.
所以它表示声音变得越来越柔和。
Okay.
好的。
And what about pianissimo?
那“极弱”呢？
Pianissimo is basically an indication.
“极弱”基本上是一种指示。
It also comes from Italian.
它也来自意大利语。
It's an indication that a player, a musician should play something very, very, very quietly.
它指示演奏者或音乐家要非常、非常、非常轻柔地演奏。
It's almost like a whisper.
几乎就像耳语一样。
Okay.
好的。
So all these three words have to do with the volume of or how loud or not so loud you play
所以这三个词都与音量有关，也就是你演奏时声音的大小或轻柔程度。
the instrument.
乐器。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, moving on now, we talk about accidentals.
嗯，现在我们继续，来谈谈变音记号。
Okay.
好的。
This is important.
这很重要。
Remember earlier we were talking about scales.
还记得之前我们讨论过音阶吗？
Well, for example, the G scale has one sharp.
比如，G大调音阶有一个升号。
So that's an F sharp.
那就是升F。
So if I'm playing it on the piano, there are seven white keys and one black key.
所以如果我在钢琴上弹奏，会有七个白键和一个黑键。
Okay.
好的。
So actually here they mentioned G sharp and then something like G natural.
所以实际上他们这里提到了升G，然后还有像还原G这样的东西。
All this, just like for everyone that's out there is complete Chinese to me.
所有这些，对我来说就像天书一样。
I have no idea what this is all about.
我完全不知道这是怎么回事。
So you have the accidentals and G sharp and you're describing something about sharpness
所以你提到了变音记号和升G，你在描述关于升号的东西
with accidentals.
和变音记号。
That's right.
没错。
So basically if you look at a piano, you have white keys.
基本上，如果你看一架钢琴，有白键。
Those are natural.
那些是自然音。
They don't have a sharp or a flat.
它们没有升号或降号。
The sharps and flats are actually played on the black keys.
升号和降号实际上是在黑键上演奏的。
Usually it's a half step from a normal note.
通常它比正常音符高半个音。
So G, it's a half step.
所以G，就是半个音。
We're talking about different keys.
我们在讨论不同的调。
So if something is in the key of G, all of you music people know what this is, key of
所以如果某首曲子是G调，所有懂音乐的人都知道这是什么，G调
G, there's one accidental.
有一个临时记号。
What's the accidental?
临时记号是什么？
It's always F sharp.
总是升F。
And so an accidental means a sharp or a flat in that key.
所以临时记号指的是那个调里的升号或降号。
Okay.
好的。
So when we talk about sharps on the piano, they're basically the black keys.
所以当我们谈论钢琴上的升号时，它们基本上就是黑键。
Yes.
是的。
Well, sharps and flats can both be black keys.
嗯，升号和降号都可以是黑键。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, apart from accidentals and G sharp, G natural, the teacher also talked about a
嗯，除了临时记号和升G、还原G，老师还讲到了
bass clef.
低音谱号。
Okay.
好的。
This is important for people who play lower instruments like the bass, you know, the upright
这对演奏低音乐器的人很重要，比如贝斯，你知道，那种大的立式
bass that big one or people who play the piano, obviously, this represents a way of writing
贝斯，或者弹钢琴的人，显然，这代表了一种记谱方式
the lower notes.
用于低音。
Okay.
好的。
So you see the lines, those five lines on paper and people write the notes.
所以你看到那些线，纸上的五条线，人们把音符写上去。
Well, sometimes they're for higher instruments, you know, the flute or the trumpet.
嗯，有时它们是为高音乐器准备的，比如长笛或小号。
But sometimes when they're for lower instruments, like the left hand of a piano or for the upright
但有时当它们是为低音乐器准备的，比如钢琴的左手部分或立式
bass, you have to write it in a special register, a special part of the sound kind of continuum.
贝斯，你必须用一种特殊的音域来写，一种声音连续体的特殊部分。
And that's the treble.
那是高音谱号。
That's the bass clef.
那是低音谱号。
Okay.
好的。
So basically, if anyone has ever seen piano notes, it tells you what to play with your
所以基本上，如果有人看过钢琴谱，它会告诉你用
left hand and your right hand.
左手和右手弹什么。
So I imagine the bass clef will be everything that's on your left hand because that sounds
所以我猜低音谱号就是你左手弹的所有东西，因为那听起来
like deeper, graver, right?
更深沉、更沉重，对吧？
Yeah, it's lower.
是的，它更低。
So it's lower on the scale instead of like up high up here where it's on the treble clef.
所以它在音阶上更低，而不是像高音谱号那样在高处。
All right.
好的。
So, oh, so the opposite would be the treble clef.
所以，哦，那么相反的就是高音谱号。
That's right.
没错。
The treble clef is up higher.
高音谱号更高。
It's most other instruments like the trumpet.
它适用于大多数其他乐器，比如小号。
The bass clef is for lower instruments.
低音谱号适用于低音乐器。
And that just means that the way that you read the music on the page is a little bit
而这只是意味着你在谱面上读谱的方式有点
different.
不同。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, we also got into things like tempo and the piece was described as andante.
嗯，我们还谈到了速度之类的东西，那首曲子被描述为行板。
Andante.
行板。
This is a very Italian word.
这是一个非常意大利语的词。
Okay, so andante means that something is played slowly.
好的，所以行板意味着某首曲子演奏得缓慢。
Okay.
好的。
So apart from andante, if so, it's a style or a tempo.
所以除了行板，如果这样，它是一种风格或速度。
I guess tempo is the speed of which is played, right?
我猜速度就是演奏的快慢，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
But you're right to say that it's also a style because in many symphonies, for example, there's
但你说它也是一种风格是对的，因为在许多交响乐中，例如，有
a movement, a part of the symphony that's called the andante.
一个乐章，交响乐的一部分，叫做行板。
And that's when everything starts to get slow and serious or pretty.
那时一切都开始变得缓慢、严肃或优美。
I've heard, I don't know, in piano, I've heard of something called staccato.
我听说过，我不知道，在钢琴里，我听说过一种叫断奏的东西。
And I think this is also related to tempo, right?
我想这也和速度有关，对吧？
Staccato is the way that you play something.
断奏是你演奏的方式。
So instead of having these long, pretty notes, you're playing them like this.
所以不是弹奏这些悠长优美的音符，而是像这样弹奏它们。
They're very, very sharp.
它们非常非常尖锐。
Like a machine gun.
像机关枪一样。
Okay, so but it's not related to the tempo.
好的，但它和速度无关。
It's kind of more just like the way that you press the keys.
它更像是你按琴键的方式。
Exactly.
完全正确。
It's a style for playing.
这是一种演奏风格。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
Well, the teacher also told the student to be careful where they lift the foot off the
嗯，老师还告诉学生要小心抬起脚离开
pedal.
踏板的位置。
And the student said, I'm just so sorry.
学生说，我真的很抱歉。
The stretch for that octave is always hard to make.
那个八度的跨度总是很难做到。
Okay, so an octave is really, really important in music.
好的，所以八度在音乐中非常重要。
Like we were talking about earlier with a scale, a scale is eight notes.
就像我们之前讨论的音阶，一个音阶有八个音符。
Well, the root, the place the word octave comes from is the number eight, like an octagon.
嗯，八度这个词的来源是数字八，就像八边形。
So octave means eight notes together, or like low C, high C, that's an octave.
所以八度意味着八个音符在一起，或者像低C、高C，那就是一个八度。
So think about the piano, when you're putting your fingers on the keys, covering eight keys
所以想想钢琴，当你把手指放在琴键上，覆盖八个键
means you have to stretch your thumb and your pinky out really, really far.
意味着你必须把拇指和小指伸得非常非常远。
And so he's saying, sorry, it's hard for me to do this because the octave, that stretch
所以他说，抱歉，我很难做到这个，因为八度，那个跨度
is really hard for my hand.
对我的手来说真的很难。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So this is different from an eighth, right?
所以这和八分之一音符不一样，对吧？
Well, it depends.
嗯，这要看情况。
Are you talking about eighth note?
你是在说八分音符吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Because I just came into the night because an octave is eight and an eighth note is different,
因为我刚进来，因为八度是八个音，而八分音符不一样，
I imagine.
我想。
Yeah.
是的。
Well, you heard in the dialogue, 16th note, eighth note.
嗯，你在对话里听到了，十六分音符、八分音符。
That's actually talking about the length of a note, how long you hold it.
这实际上说的是音符的长度，就是你按住它多久。
Okay.
好的。
So basically you're saying it's the way you measure the music.
所以基本上你是说这是衡量音乐的方式。
You can have four count or three count, but you divide that into pieces.
你可以有四拍或三拍，但你要把它分成小块。
It's like a pie in math where you divide it into pieces.
就像数学里的馅饼，你把它切成小块。
So if it's a 16th note or an eighth note, that's the length based on the kind of music
所以如果是十六分音符或八分音符，那就是基于你演奏的音乐类型决定的长度，
you're playing.
你演奏的。
So I imagine 16th note is shorter than eighth.
所以我猜十六分音符比八分音符短。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
At least I got that one right.
至少这个我猜对了。
And 32nd note is shorter than a 16th note.
而三十二分音符比十六分音符短。
Wow.
哇。
You have all the way up to 32nd.
一直有到三十二分音符。
64th note is shorter.
六十四分音符更短。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
Okay.
好的。
It gets very complicated, very mathy.
这变得非常复杂，非常数学化。
All right.
好吧。
And towards the end, the teacher recommended for Cody to watch his dynamics.
在结尾，老师建议科迪注意他的力度。
What does she mean with watch your dynamics?
她说的“注意你的力度”是什么意思？
I used to get this all the time in music.
我在音乐课上经常听到这个。
So you're concentrating on your music, you're playing, you're getting the notes and Cody
所以当你专注于音乐，你在演奏，你在弹对音符，而科迪
is stretching his hands.
在伸展他的手。
The octaves are so far away and he forgets to play it loud or soft because on the page
八度音程太远了，他忘了弹得大声或小声，因为谱子上
it says like we heard earlier, decrescendo.
写着像我们之前听到的，渐弱。
So get much, much softer.
所以要变得非常非常轻柔。
So Cody completely forgot.
所以科迪完全忘了。
He's not listening.
他没在听。
He's not reading the page and seeing what it says about the volume of the music.
他没在读谱子，看上面关于音乐音量的说明。
So basically the dynamics are like the instructions of how loud to play it or not so loud.
所以基本上力度就像是指令，告诉你弹得多大声或不太大声。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So does it say pianissimo or the opposite?
所以上面写的是极弱还是相反？
Does it say forte?
写的是强吗？
And it will actually say this on the notes.
而且它实际上会写在音符上。
Yes.
是的。
Forte, it'll say that.
强，它会那样写。
F-O-R-T-E or sometimes just F.
F-O-R-T-E 或者有时只是 F。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
So P is piano.
所以 P 是弱。
That means like we said earlier, quiet.
那意思是像我们之前说的，安静。
Pianissimo is P, P, P. It's very, very quiet.
极弱是 P、P、P，非常非常安静。
F is forte, loud.
F 是强，大声。
Okay.
好的。
So I think, well, if anyone out there plays an instrument you can relate and you can maybe
所以我想，嗯，如果有人演奏乐器，你们能感同身受，也许
know about these things that you may know it in your original language.
知道这些术语，可能用你们的母语也知道。
I know many people who play musical instruments and don't really know the technical words
我认识很多演奏乐器的人，但不太知道这些术语的
in their original language.
母语说法。
I mean, things like Andante and pianissimo, things like this, I think are universal, right?
我的意思是，像行板和极弱这样的词，我觉得是通用的，对吧？
They're used in whatever language.
它们在任何语言里都用。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Very, very widely used.
非常非常广泛地使用。
But things like the accidentals or bass clef or scales and stuff like that, I think it's
但像临时记号、低音谱号或音阶之类的东西，我觉得
obviously different languages.
显然不同语言不一样。
For example, you know Italian, like scales or accidentals, are they?
比如，你知道意大利语，像音阶或临时记号，是吗？
They're different.
它们不一样。
They're different, right?
它们不一样，对吧？
They're different.
它们不一样。
All of the other words.
所有其他词。
So the instructions on the page, because music is shared all over the world, the instructions
所以谱子上的指令，因为音乐在全世界共享，谱子上的
on the page are almost always in Italian, so piano, andante, or they're in German.
指令几乎总是意大利语，比如弱、行板，或者是德语。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Some music.
有些音乐。
And everything else, scales, octaves, these are all in your native language.
其他所有东西，音阶、八度，这些都是用你的母语。
And so they're very, very important to study if you want to play and I think very, very
所以如果你想演奏，这些非常重要去学习，而且我觉得非常非常
useful if you want to study an instrument.
有用如果你想学一种乐器。
Yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
I think it's also a very good idea to just have a general knowledge about these things
我觉得对这些东西有个大致了解也是个好主意，
because sometimes it's nice to know a little bit about it and maybe if a friend is talking
因为有时候知道一点挺好的，也许如果朋友在谈论
about music, you can maybe understand a little bit more about what it's like.
音乐，你能多理解一点它是什么样的。
Or if you see music, a sheet of music, you can now more or less know what's going on
或者如果你看到乐谱，一张乐谱，你现在或多或少能明白上面那些图画和潦草的小符号是什么意思了。
with all those drawings and little scribbles there.
那些图画和潦草的小符号。
Absolutely.
完全正确。
And if you have any questions, of course, you're welcome to come to our website and
如果你有任何问题，当然，欢迎来到我们的网站，
ask or share your experiences as Marco has just said.
像Marco刚才说的那样提问或分享你的经验。
So please come to EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys next time.
我们下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Let's David!
加油，David！